export const CHRISTIANRELIGIOUSSTUDIESA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. On the fourth day, God created the sun, moon and stars for the following purposes except",
A: "to separate the day from the night",
B: "for signs of seasons, days and years",
C: "to give light upon the earth",
D: "to dry up flood from the face of the earth",
answer: "D. to dry up flood from the face of the earth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Which of the following was not a river flowing from the Garden of Eden?",
A: "Gihon",
B: "Tigris",
C: "Euphrates",
D: "Kishon",
answer: "D. Kishon",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. When Eve was about to be created, God did all the following except",
A: "causing a deep sleep to fall on Adam",
B: "taking a rib from Adam's side",
C: "covering where he removed the rib with a bone",
D: "using the rib to create Eve",
answer: "C. covering where he removed the rib with a bone",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. 'You shall be my own possession among all peoples' God made this promise to the Israelites on the condition that they",
A: "drove the Canaanites out of the land",
B: "kept away from foreign women",
C: "obeyed God's voice and kept His covenant",
D: "taught their children to obey God",
answer: "C. obeyed God's voice and kept His covenant",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Jacob's special robe for Joseph portrayed him as a",
A: "prince",
B: "heir",
C: "prophet",
D: "priest",
answer: "B. heir",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The names of the sons of Jacob listed in the book of Exodus excluded Joseph because",
A: "Joseph was represented by his two sons",
B: "the Israelites thought Joseph had died",
C: "the list covered only those who came to Egypt with Jacob",
D: "it was an oversight on the part of the writers",
answer: "A. Joseph was represented by his two sons",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. The boy Moses was hidden for three months because",
A: "he was destined to become a great leader",
B: "he was attacked by an abominable disease",
C: "Pharoah feared the growth of the Hebrew population",
D: "Pharoah had decreed the murder of Hebrew male borns",
answer: "D. Pharoah had decreed the murder of Hebrew male borns",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The sons of Samuel misused their privileged positions by",
A: "not allowing the fats of animals to burn first to God",
B: "sleeping with women who came to sacrifice",
C: "bribery and false judgement",
D: "stealing from the offering",
answer: "C. bribery and false judgment",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. 'Put me I pray you in one of the priest's places that I may eat a morsel of bread' Who made this prophecy and to whom was it made?",
A: "Eli to Hophni and Phineas",
B: "A man of God to Eli",
C: "Samuel to Eli the priest",
D: "A prophet to Eli's sons",
answer: "B. A man of God to Eli",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Saul lied to Samuel when he (Saul)",
A: "allowed the soldiers to bring the booties of the war home",
B: "said that he had utterly destroyed the Amalekites",
C: "failed to kill the King of the Amalekites",
D: "spared the Kenites in the war against the Amalekites",
answer: "B. said that he had utterly destroyed the Amalekites",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Solomon told Hiram, King of Tyre that he had decided to build a temple for the Lord because",
A: "the Lord had given him peace and all good things",
B: "his father David never intended to build one",
C: "he wanted to force Hiram to come to his aid",
D: "Hiram had entered into a marriage alliance with his father",
answer: "A. the Lord had given him peace and all good things",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. During the Ammonite war, Uriah disobeyed King David by refusing to go to his house to sleep because",
A: "it was wrong to go home drunk",
B: "his wife would regard him as a coward",
C: "it would be unpatriotic to break military vow",
D: "he suspected that the king had lost interest in the battle",
answer: "C. it would be unpatriotic to break the military vow",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. Nathan announced all the following forms of punishment for David's sin except that",
A: "God will raise up evil against his own house",
B: "his wives will be taken away from him",
C: "the sword will never depart from his house",
D: "his son Absalom will challenge him",
answer: "D. his son Absalom will challenge him",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. The wife of Phineas named her premature child Ichabod because",
A: "Israel had lost the Ark and her husband",
B: "the Philistines suffered a lot of casualties",
C: "her husband treated the Lord's sacrifice with contempt",
D: "Eli failed to restrain his children",
answer: "A. Israel had lost the Ark and her husband",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The main lesson to be learnt from Elijah's victory at Mount Carmel is",
A: "God empowers his prophets",
B: "the failure of false prophets",
C: "God's supremacy over false gods",
D: "ability to bring fire from heaven",
answer: "C. God's supremacy over false gods",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. When Elijah confronted Ahab over the killing of Naboth, Ahab",
A: "rejected any responsibility for it",
B: "blamed Jezebel for the order",
C: "repented with sackcloth and fasting",
D: "reluctantly accepted responsibility for it",
answer: "C. repented with sackcloth and fasting",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Gehazi became a leper because of his",
A: "deceitfulness",
B: "greed",
C: "wickedness",
D: "lies",
answer: "B. greed",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Which of the following events could be attributed to Josiah?",
A: "Establishing relationship with Assyria",
B: "Reconstruction of the valley of Hinnon",
C: "Revival of the feast of the Passover",
D: "Building walls around Jerusalem",
answer: "C. Revival of the feast of the Passover",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Huldah, the prophetess announced evil upon Judah and its inhabitants because people",
A: "had burned incense to other gods",
B: "were marrying foreign women",
C: "were disobedient to the law of God",
D: "had failed to keep the sabbath",
answer: "A. had burned incense to other gods",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. According to Ezra, the return of the Jews from exile was prophesied by",
A: "Ezekiel",
B: "Amos",
C: "Isiaiah",
D: "Jeremiah",
answer: "D. Jeremiah",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Nebuchadnezzar allowed the Chaldeans, Syrians and Moabites to attack Judah so that Judah might",
A: "learn a lesson",
B: "be destroyed",
C: "face famine",
D: "ransack the temple",
answer: "A. learn a lesson",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Which of the following distinctly demonstrates the episode of Shadrach, Meshack and Abednego?",
A: "complete trust in God",
B: "God's ability to save his servants",
C: "Weakness of an earthly king",
D: "Failure of a king's dictatorship",
answer: "A. complete trust in God",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The indigenous official of King Darius was unhappy with Daniel because he",
A: "often reported them to the king",
B: "was a Jewish exile",
C: "had an excellent spirit",
D: "refused to worship the golden image",
answer: "C. had an excellent spirit",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. 'I gave you cleanness of teeth in all your cities'. This statement means God gave them",
A: "no water to drink",
B: "new set of teeth",
C: "no food to eat",
D: "no teeth at all",
answer: "C. no food to eat",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. 'O seer go, flee away to the land of Judah and eat bread'. This means Amos was to",
A: "go and earn his living in Judah",
B: "go and settle in Judah",
C: "live only on bread in Judah",
D: "run to Judah and bake bread",
answer: "A. go and earn his living in Judah",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. Hosea named his first son Jezreel as a sign of",
A: "victory upon the enemies of Israel",
B: "punishment to come unto the royal house",
C: "God losing his patience for Israel",
D: "breaking the covenant relationship with Israel",
answer: "B. punishment to come unto the royal house",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. 'Don't be afraid, henceforth you will be catching men'. 'Catching men' means capturing men",
A: "to the new faith",
B: "who oppose the Gospel",
C: "who are useful",
D: "who are spiritual",
answer: "A. to the new faith",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The man who was forced to carry the cross of Jesus was",
A: "Joseph of Arimathea",
B: "Nicodemus",
C: "Simon of Cyrene",
D: "Simon the Zealot",
answer: "C. Simon of Cyrene",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Golgotha means the place of",
A: "the dead",
B: "crucifixion",
C: "sacrifice",
D: "the skull",
answer: "D. the skull",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. A Roman Centurion was in charge of",
A: "1,000 soldiers",
B: "500 soldiers",
C: "200 soldiers",
D: "100 soldiers",
answer: "D. 100 soldiers",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. The tearing of the temple curtain into two meant",
A: "there was the need for a new curtain",
B: "Gentiles would now enter the Holy of Holies",
C: "all men would now worship freely in the Temple",
D: "there was now open access to God",
answer: "D. there was now open access to God",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Cleopas' heart burnt within him on the road to Emmaus when Jesus",
A: "appeared to them",
B: "taught them the scriptures",
C: "broke bread with them",
D: "walked with them",
answer: "B. taught them the scriptures",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. According to Matthew, when the women met the risen Jesus, they",
A: "anointed him with spices",
B: "took hold of his feet and worshipped him",
C: "told him the whereabouts of the disciples",
D: "asked him to accompany them",
answer: "B. took hold of his feet and worshipped him",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Life in the Early Church was characterized by",
A: "fasting and alms-giving",
B: "prophetic activities",
C: "communal spirit",
D: "honesty and peace",
answer: "C. communal spirit",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The appointment of deacons in the Early Church was meant to check",
A: "discrimination and favoritism",
B: "dishonesty and stealing",
C: "cheating and tribalism",
D: "greediness and lying",
answer: "A. discrimination and favoritism",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. One remarkable thing about the feast of Pentecost for Christians was that it",
A: "attracted many foreigners into Israel",
B: "enabled people to speak in tongues",
C: "marked the celebration of grain harvest",
D: "brought home many Jewish nationals",
answer: "B. enabled people to speak in tongues",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The charge of drunkenness was leveled against the apostles on Pentecost day because",
A: "they were drunk before nine o’clock",
B: "they spoke in other tongues",
C: "a power descended on them",
D: "they made an unintelligent noise",
answer: "B. they spoke in other tongues",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which prophet did Peter quote when he preached on Pentecost day about the spirit falling upon all men?",
A: "Amos",
B: "Hosea",
C: "Joel",
D: "Jonah",
answer: "C. Joel",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The boldness of Peter and John before the Sanhedrin was attributed to",
A: "their having great influence",
B: "possession of great strength",
C: "their being with Jesus",
D: "their ability to defend themselves",
answer: "C. their being with Jesus",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Peter's tour of Lydda led to the",
A: "development of the church in Caesarea",
B: "conversion of the residents of Sharon",
C: "conversion of Cornelius and his household",
D: "healing of Dorcas and her family",
answer: "B. conversion of the residents of Sharon",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. 'Dress yourself and put on your sandals' Obedience to this instruction led to",
A: "an angel's destruction of Herod",
B: "Peter's arrest and imprisonment",
C: "Peter's release from prison",
D: "the disciples' escape from Herod",
answer: "C. Peter's release from prison",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Partially, according to James, is practiced in the church by",
A: "neglecting the poor",
B: "misusing the church funds",
C: "respecting the educated members",
D: "offering service to non-believers",
answer: "A. neglecting the poor",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. 'Abraham believed God and it was reckoned to him as righteousness' James used this text to highlight his teaching on",
A: "effective prayer",
B: "faith and works",
C: "counseling",
D: "impartiality",
answer: "B. faith and works",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. James taught that Christians should offer prayers of thanksgiving when they are",
A: "remorseful",
B: "sick",
C: "interceding",
D: "cheerful",
answer: "D. cheerful",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. James advised against looking down on the poor because they are",
A: "the rightful heirs of the kingdom",
B: "those who spent time on the Lord",
C: "those who contribute little but do a lot",
D: "for peace and self-sacrifice",
answer: "A. the rightful heirs of the kingdom",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. As they were sharing Christ's sufferings, Peter advised Christians to",
A: "be prayerful",
B: "rejoice",
C: "be truthful",
D: "persevere",
answer: "B. rejoice",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Peter described Christians as a chosen race of God because they",
A: "declared God's wonderful deeds",
B: "had all become ordained men",
C: "had continued to live their usual lives",
D: "had displaced the Jews completely in God's rating",
answer: "A. declared God's wonderful deeds",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. 'Live as free men, yet without using your freedom as pretext for evil' Peter by this text was calling on Christians to",
A: "resist the devil always",
B: "do what is right",
C: "fight for their freedom",
D: "endure pain while suffering",
answer: "B. do what is right",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Peter believed that God appreciates and gives credit to servants who",
A: "pray without ceasing",
B: "keep their tongues shut",
C: "fail to honor wicked masters",
D: "suffer for wrongs not done",
answer: "D. suffer for wrongs not done",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Peter admonished church leaders to take care of the flock of Christ in order to",
A: "restrain men from degrading the church",
B: "obtain God's crown of glory",
C: "build a vibrant church",
D: "ensure discipline in the church",
answer: "B. obtain God's crown of glory",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]